<?xml version="1.0"?>
<docs>
    <members name="SqlDataSourceEnumerator">
    <SqlDataSourceEnumerator>
    <summary>Provides a mechanism for enumerating all available instances of SQL Server within the local network.</summary>
    <remarks>
      <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
SQL Server makes it possible for applications to determine the existence of its instances within the current network. The <xref:Microsoft.Data.Sql.SqlDataSourceEnumerator> class exposes this information to the application developer, providing a <xref:System.Data.DataTable> containing information about all the available servers. This returned table contains a list of server instances that matches the list provided when a user attempts to create a new connection, and on the `Connection Properties` dialog box, expands the drop-down list containing all the available servers.  

 ]]></format>
    </remarks>
    <related type="Article" href="/dotnet/framework/data/adonet/sql/enumerating-instances-of-sql-server">Enumerating Instances of SQL Server</related>
  </SqlDataSourceEnumerator>
   <GetDataSources>
        <summary>Retrieves a <see cref="T:System.Data.DataTable" /> containing information about all visible SQL Server instances.</summary>
        <returns>A <see cref="T:System.Data.DataTable" /> containing information about the visible SQL Server instances.</returns>
        <remarks>
          <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
The table returned by this method contains the following columns, all of which contain strings:  

|Column|Description|  
|------------|-----------------|  
|**ServerName**|Name of the server.|  
|**InstanceName**|Name of the server instance. Blank if the server is running as the default instance.|  
|**IsClustered**|Indicates whether the server is part of a cluster.|  
|**Version**|Version of the server:<br /><br />10.0.xx for SQL Server 2008<br />10.50.x for SQL Server 2008 R2<br />11.0.xx for SQL Server 2012<br />12.0.xx for SQL Server 2014<br />13.0.xx for SQL Server 2016<br />14.0.xx for SQL Server 2017|  
  
> [!NOTE]
> Due to the nature of the mechanism used by <xref:Microsoft.Data.Sql.SqlDataSourceEnumerator> to locate data sources on a network, the method will not always return a complete list of the available servers, and the list might not be the same on every call. If you plan to use this function to let users select a server from a list, make sure that you always also supply an option to type in a name that is not in the list, in case the server enumeration does not return all the available servers. In addition, this method may take a significant amount of time to execute, so be careful about calling it when performance is critical.  

## Examples  
 The following console application retrieves information about all the visible SQL Server instances and displays the information in the console window.  
  
[!code-csharp[SqlDataSourceEnumerator.Example#1](~/../sqlclient/doc/samples/SqlDataSourceEnumeratorExample.cs#1)]
  
 ]]></format>
        </remarks>
        <related type="Article" href="/dotnet/framework/data/adonet/sql/enumerating-instances-of-sql-server">Enumerating Instances of SQL Server</related>
      </GetDataSources>
    <Instance>
        <summary>Gets an instance of the <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.Sql.SqlDataSourceEnumerator"/>, which can be used to retrieve information about available SQL Server instances.</summary>
        <value>An instance of the <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.Sql.SqlDataSourceEnumerator"/> used to retrieve information about available SQL Server instances.</value>
        <remarks>
          <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
The <xref:Microsoft.Data.Sql.SqlDataSourceEnumerator> class does not provide a constructor. Use the <xref:Microsoft.Data.Sql.SqlDataSourceEnumerator.Instance%2A> property to retrieve an instance of the class instead.  

[!code-csharp[SqlDataSourceEnumeratorExample#1](~/../sqlclient/doc/samples/SqlDataSourceEnumeratorExample.cs#1)]

## Examples  
The following console application displays a list of all the available SQL Server 2005 instances within the local network. This code uses the <xref:System.Data.DataTable.Select%2A> method to filter the rows in the table returned by the <xref:Microsoft.Data.Sql.SqlDataSourceEnumerator.GetDataSources%2A> method.  
 [!code-csharp[SqlDataSourceEnumeratorVersionExample#1](~/../sqlclient/doc/samples/SqlDataSourceEnumeratorVersionExample.cs#1)]

 ]]></format>
        </remarks>
        <related type="Article" href="/dotnet/framework/data/adonet/sql/enumerating-instances-of-sql-server">Enumerating Instances of SQL Server</related>
    
    </Instance>
    </members>
</docs>
