<?xml version="1.0"?>
<docs>
    <members name="TriggerAction">
        <TriggerAction>
            <summary>The <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.Server.TriggerAction" /> enumeration is used by the <see cref="T:Microsoft.SqlServer.Server.SqlTriggerContext" /> class to indicate what action fired the trigger.</summary>
            <remarks>
            <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 The <xref:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.Server.TriggerAction> enumeration is used by the <xref:Microsoft.SqlServer.Server.SqlTriggerContext> class to indicate what action fired the trigger.
  
 ]]></format>
            </remarks>
        </TriggerAction>
        <AlterAppRole>
            <summary>An ALTER APPLICATION ROLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterAppRole>
        <AlterAssembly>
            <summary>An ALTER ASSEMBLY Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterAssembly>
        <AlterBinding>
            <summary>An ALTER_REMOTE_SERVICE_BINDING event type was specified when an event notification was created on the database or server instance.</summary>
        </AlterBinding>
        <AlterFunction>
            <summary>An ALTER FUNCTION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterFunction>
        <AlterIndex>
            <summary>An ALTER INDEX Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterIndex>
        <AlterLogin>
            <summary>An ALTER LOGIN Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterLogin>
        <AlterPartitionFunction>
            <summary>An ALTER PARTITION FUNCTION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterPartitionFunction>
        <AlterPartitionScheme>
            <summary>An ALTER PARTITION SCHEME Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterPartitionScheme>
        <AlterProcedure>
            <summary>An ALTER PROCEDURE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterProcedure>
        <AlterQueue>
            <summary>An ALTER QUEUE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterQueue>
        <AlterRole>
            <summary>An ALTER ROLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterRole>
        <AlterRoute>
            <summary>An ALTER ROUTE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterRoute>
        <AlterSchema>
            <summary>An ALTER SCHEMA Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterSchema>
        <AlterService>
            <summary>An ALTER SERVICE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterService>
        <AlterTable>
            <summary>An ALTER TABLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterTable>
        <AlterTrigger>
            <summary>An ALTER TRIGGER Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterTrigger>
        <AlterUser>
            <summary>An ALTER USER Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterUser>
        <AlterView>
            <summary>An ALTER VIEW Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </AlterView>
        <CreateAppRole>
            <summary>A CREATE APPLICATION ROLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateAppRole>
        <CreateAssembly>
            <summary>A CREATE ASSEMBLY Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateAssembly>
        <CreateBinding>
            <summary>A CREATE_REMOTE_SERVICE_BINDING event type was specified when an event notification was created on the database or server instance.</summary>
        </CreateBinding>
        <CreateContract>
            <summary>A CREATE CONTRACT Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateContract>
        <CreateEventNotification>
            <summary>A CREATE EVENT NOTIFICATION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateEventNotification>
        <CreateFunction>
            <summary>A CREATE FUNCTION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateFunction>
        <CreateIndex>
            <summary>A CREATE INDEX Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateIndex>
        <CreateLogin>
            <summary>A CREATE LOGIN Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateLogin>
        <CreateMsgType>
            <summary>A CREATE MESSAGE TYPE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateMsgType>
        <CreatePartitionFunction>
            <summary>A CREATE PARTITION FUNCTION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreatePartitionFunction>
        <CreatePartitionScheme>
            <summary>A CREATE PARTITION SCHEME Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreatePartitionScheme>
        <CreateProcedure>
            <summary>A CREATE PROCEDURE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateProcedure>
        <CreateQueue>
            <summary>A CREATE QUEUE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateQueue>
        <CreateRole>
            <summary>A CREATE ROLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateRole>
        <CreateRoute>
            <summary>A CREATE ROUTE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateRoute>
        <CreateSchema>
            <summary>A CREATE SCHEMA Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateSchema>
        <CreateSecurityExpression>
            <summary>Not available.</summary>
        </CreateSecurityExpression>
        <CreateService>
            <summary>A CREATE SERVICE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateService>
        <CreateSynonym>
            <summary>A CREATE SYNONYM Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateSynonym>
        <CreateTable>
            <summary>A CREATE TABLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateTable>
        <CreateTrigger>
            <summary>A CREATE TRIGGER Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateTrigger>
        <CreateType>
            <summary>A CREATE TYPE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateType>
        <CreateUser>
            <summary>A CREATE USER Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateUser>
        <CreateView>
            <summary>A CREATE VIEW Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </CreateView>
        <Delete>
            <summary>A DELETE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </Delete>
        <DenyObject>
            <summary>A DENY Object Permissions Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DenyObject>
        <DenyStatement>
            <summary>A DENY Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DenyStatement>
        <DropAppRole>
            <summary>A DROP APPLICATION ROLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropAppRole>
        <DropAssembly>
            <summary>A DROP ASSEMBLY Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropAssembly>
        <DropBinding>
            <summary>A DROP_REMOTE_SERVICE_BINDING event type was specified when an event notification was created on the database or server instance.</summary>
        </DropBinding>
        <DropContract>
            <summary>A DROP CONTRACT Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropContract>
        <DropEventNotification>
            <summary>A DROP EVENT NOTIFICATION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropEventNotification>
        <DropFunction>
            <summary>A DROP FUNCTION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropFunction>
        <DropIndex>
            <summary>A DROP INDEX Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropIndex>
        <DropLogin>
            <summary>A DROP LOGIN Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropLogin>
        <DropMsgType>
            <summary>A DROP MESSAGE TYPE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropMsgType>
        <DropPartitionFunction>
            <summary>A DROP PARTITION FUNCTION Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropPartitionFunction>
        <DropPartitionScheme>
            <summary>A DROP PARTITION SCHEME Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropPartitionScheme>
        <DropProcedure>
            <summary>A DROP PROCEDURE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropProcedure>
        <DropQueue>
            <summary>A DROP QUEUE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropQueue>
        <DropRole>
            <summary>A DROP ROLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropRole>
        <DropRoute>
            <summary>A DROP ROUTE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropRoute>
        <DropSchema>
            <summary>A DROP SCHEMA Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropSchema>
        <DropSecurityExpression>
            <summary>Not available.</summary>
        </DropSecurityExpression>
        <DropService>
            <summary>A DROP SERVICE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropService>
        <DropSynonym>
            <summary>A DROP SYNONYM Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropSynonym>
        <DropTable>
            <summary>A DROP TABLE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropTable>
        <DropTrigger>
            <summary>A DROP TRIGGER Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropTrigger>
        <DropType>
            <summary>A DROP TYPE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropType>
        <DropUser>
            <summary>A DROP USER Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropUser>
        <DropView>
            <summary>A DROP VIEW Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </DropView>
        <GrantObject>
            <summary>A GRANT OBJECT Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </GrantObject>
        <GrantStatement>
            <summary>A GRANT Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </GrantStatement>
        <Insert>
            <summary>An INSERT Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </Insert>
        <Invalid>
            <summary>An invalid trigger action, one that is not exposed to the user, occurred.</summary>
        </Invalid>
        <RevokeObject>
            <summary>A REVOKE OBJECT Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </RevokeObject>
        <RevokeStatement>
            <summary>A REVOKE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </RevokeStatement>
        <Update>
            <summary>An UPDATE Transact-SQL statement was executed.</summary>
        </Update>
    </members>
</docs>
