<docs>
  <members name="SqlAuthenticationProvider">
    <SqlAuthenticationProvider>
      <summary>Defines the core behavior of authentication providers and provides a base class for derived classes. </summary>
      <remarks>
        <format type="text/markdown">
          <![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 Derived classes must provide a parameterless constructor if they can be instantiated from the app.config file.

## Examples  
 The following example demonstrates implementing a custom SqlAuthenticationProvider and providing the same to SqlClient for overriding Device Code Flow authentication mode:
 
 [!code-csharp[ActiveDirectory_DeviceCodeFlowCallback Example#1](~/../sqlclient/doc/samples/CustomDeviceCodeFlowAzureAuthenticationProvider.cs#1)]
  
 ]]>
        </format>
      </remarks>
    </SqlAuthenticationProvider>
    <ctor>
      <summary>
        Called from constructors in derived classes to initialize the <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlAuthenticationProvider" /> class.
      </summary>
    </ctor>
    <GetProvider>
      <param name="authenticationMethod">The authentication method.</param>
      <summary>Gets an authentication provider by method.</summary>
      <returns>
        The authentication provider or <see langword="null" /> if not found.
      </returns>
      <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
    </GetProvider>
    <SetProvider>
      <param name="authenticationMethod">The authentication method.</param>
      <param name="provider">The authentication provider.</param>
      <summary>Sets an authentication provider by method.</summary>
      <returns>
        <see langword="true" /> if the operation succeeded; otherwise, <see langword="false" /> (for example, the existing provider disallows overriding).
      </returns>
      <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
    </SetProvider>
    <BeforeLoad>
      <param name="authenticationMethod">The authentication method.</param>
      <summary>This method is called immediately before the provider is added to SQL drivers registry. </summary>
      <remarks>Avoid performing long-waiting tasks in this method, since it can block other threads from accessing the provider registry.</remarks>
    </BeforeLoad>
    <BeforeUnload>
      <param name="authenticationMethod">The authentication method.</param>
      <summary>This method is called immediately before the provider is removed from the SQL drivers registry. </summary>
      <remarks>For example, this method is called when a different provider with the same authentication method overrides this provider in the SQL drivers registry. Avoid performing long-waiting task in this method, since it can block other threads from accessing the provider registry.</remarks>
    </BeforeUnload>
    <IsSupported>
      <param name="authenticationMethod">The authentication method.</param>
      <summary>Indicates whether the specified authentication method is supported.</summary>
      <returns>
        <see langword="true" /> if the specified authentication method is supported; otherwise, <see langword="false" />.
      </returns>
      <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
    </IsSupported>
    <AcquireTokenAsync>
      <param name="parameters">The Active Directory authentication parameters passed by the driver to authentication providers.</param>
      <summary>Acquires a security token from the authority.</summary>
      <returns>Represents an asynchronous operation that returns the AD authentication token.</returns>
      <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
    </AcquireTokenAsync>
  </members>
</docs>
