<docs>
    <members name="SqlColumnEncryptionEnclaveProvider">
        <SqlColumnEncryptionEnclaveProvider>
            <summary>The base class that defines the interface for enclave providers for Always Encrypted.</summary>
            <remarks>
                <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  

## Remarks  
An enclave is a protected region of memory inside SQL Server, used for computations on encrypted columns. An enclave provider encapsulates the client-side implementation details of 
the enclave attestation protocol as well as the logic for creating and caching enclave sessions.  

]]></format>
            </remarks>
        </SqlColumnEncryptionEnclaveProvider>
        <ctor>
            <summary>Initializes a new instance of the <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlColumnEncryptionEnclaveProvider" /> class</summary>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </ctor>
        <CreateEnclaveSession>
            <param name="enclaveAttestationInfo">The information the provider uses to attest the enclave and generate a symmetric key for the session. The format of this information is specific to the enclave attestation protocol.</param>
            <param name="clientDiffieHellmanKey">A Diffie-Hellman algorithm object that encapsulates a client-side key pair.</param>
            <param name="enclaveSessionParameters">The set of parameters required for an enclave session.</param>
            <param name="customData">The set of extra data needed for attestating the enclave.</param>
            <param name="customDataLength">The length of the extra data needed for attestating the enclave.</param>
            <param name="sqlEnclaveSession">The requested enclave session or <see langword="null" /> if the provider doesn't implement session caching.</param>
            <param name="counter">A counter that the enclave provider is expected to increment each time SqlClient retrieves the session from the cache. The purpose of this field is to prevent replay attacks.</param>
            <summary>When overridden in a derived class, performs enclave attestation, generates a symmetric key for the session, creates a an enclave session and stores the session information in the cache.</summary>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </CreateEnclaveSession>
        <GetAttestationParameters>
            <param name="attestationUrl">The endpoint of an attestation service for attesting the enclave.</param>
            <param name="customData">A set of extra data needed for attestating the enclave.</param>
            <param name="customDataLength">The length of the extra data needed for attestating the enclave.</param>
            <summary>Gets the information that SqlClient subsequently uses to initiate the process of attesting the enclave and to establish a secure session with the enclave.</summary>
            <returns>The information SqlClient subsequently uses to initiate the process of attesting the enclave and to establish a secure session with the enclave.</returns>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </GetAttestationParameters>
        <GetEnclaveSession>
            <param name="enclaveSessionParameters">The set of parameters required for enclave session.</param>
            <param name="generateCustomData"><see langword="true" /> to indicate that a set of extra data needs to be generated for attestation; otherwise, <see langword="false" />.</param>
            <param name="sqlEnclaveSession">When this method returns, the requested enclave session or <see langword="null" /> if the provider doesn't implement session caching. This parameter is treated as uninitialized.</param>
            <param name="counter">A counter that the enclave provider is expected to increment each time SqlClient retrieves the session from the cache. The purpose of this field is to prevent replay attacks.</param>
            <param name="customData">A set of extra data needed for attestating the enclave.</param>
            <param name="customDataLength">The length of the extra data needed for attestating the enclave.</param>
            <summary>When overridden in a derived class, looks up an existing enclave session information in the enclave session cache. If the enclave provider doesn't implement enclave session caching, this method is expected to return <see langword="null" /> in the <paramref name="sqlEnclaveSession" /> parameter.
            </summary>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </GetEnclaveSession>
        <InvalidateEnclaveSession>
            <param name="enclaveSessionParameters">The set of parameters required for enclave session.</param>
            <param name="enclaveSession">The session to be invalidated.</param>
            <summary>When overridden in a derived class, looks up and evicts an enclave session from the enclave session cache, if the provider implements session caching.</summary>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </InvalidateEnclaveSession>
    </members>
</docs>
