<?xml version="1.0"?>
<docs>
    <members name="SqlNotificationInfo">
        <SqlNotificationInfo>
            <summary>This enumeration provides additional information about the different notifications that can be received by the dependency event handler.</summary>
            <remarks>
            <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
    
## Remarks  
 The <xref:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlNotificationInfo> enumeration is referenced by an instance of the <xref:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlNotificationEventArgs> class.  
  
 ]]></format>
            </remarks>
        </SqlNotificationInfo>
        <AlreadyChanged>
            <summary>The <see langword="SqlDependency" /> object already fired, and new commands cannot be added to it.</summary>
        </AlreadyChanged>
        <Alter>
            <summary>An underlying server object related to the query was modified.</summary>
        </Alter>
        <Delete>
            <summary>Data was changed by a DELETE statement.</summary>
        </Delete>
        <Drop>
            <summary>An underlying object related to the query was dropped.</summary>
        </Drop>
        <Error>
            <summary>An internal server error occurred.</summary>
        </Error>
        <Expired>
            <summary>The <see langword="SqlDependency" /> object has expired.</summary>
        </Expired>
        <Insert>
            <summary>Data was changed by an INSERT statement.</summary>
        </Insert>
        <Invalid>
            <summary>A statement was provided that cannot be notified (for example, an UPDATE statement).</summary>
        </Invalid>
        <Isolation>
            <summary>The statement was executed under an isolation mode that was not valid (for example, Snapshot).</summary>
        </Isolation>
        <Merge>
            <summary>Used to distinguish the server-side cause for a query notification firing.</summary>
        </Merge>
        <Options>
            <summary>The SET options were not set appropriately at subscription time.</summary>
        </Options>
        <PreviousFire>
            <summary>A previous statement has caused query notifications to fire under the current transaction.</summary>
        </PreviousFire>
        <Query>
            <summary>A SELECT statement that cannot be notified or was provided.</summary>
        </Query>
        <Resource>
            <summary>Fires as a result of server resource pressure.</summary>
        </Resource>
        <Restart>
            <summary>The server was restarted (notifications are sent during restart.).</summary>
        </Restart>
        <TemplateLimit>
            <summary>The subscribing query causes the number of templates on one of the target tables to exceed the maximum allowable limit.</summary>
        </TemplateLimit>
        <Truncate>
            <summary>One or more tables were truncated.</summary>
        </Truncate>
        <Unknown>
            <summary>Used when the info option sent by the server was not recognized by the client.</summary>
        </Unknown>
        <Update>
            <summary>Data was changed by an UPDATE statement.</summary>
        </Update>
    </members>
</docs>
