<?xml version="1.0"?>
<docs>
    <members name="SqlNotificationEventArgs">
        <SqlNotificationEventArgs>
            <summary>Represents the set of arguments passed to the notification event handler.</summary>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </SqlNotificationEventArgs>
        <ctor>
            <param name="type">
            <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlNotificationType" /> value that indicates whether this notification is generated because of an actual change, or by the subscription.</param>
            <param name="info">
            <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlNotificationInfo" /> value that indicates the reason for the notification event. This may occur because the data in the store actually changed, or the notification became invalid (for example, it timed out).</param>
            <param name="source">
            <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlNotificationSource" /> value that indicates the source that generated the notification.</param>
            <summary>Creates a new instance of the <see cref="T:Microsoft.Data.SqlClient.SqlNotificationEventArgs" /> object.</summary>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </ctor>
        <Info>
            <summary>Gets a value that indicates the reason for the notification event, such as a row in the database being modified or a table being truncated.</summary>
            <value>The notification event reason.</value>
            <remarks>
            <format type="text/markdown"><![CDATA[  
  
## Remarks  
 This event may occur because the data in the store actually changed, or the notification is no longer valid (for example, it timed out).  
  
 ]]></format>
            </remarks>
        </Info>
        <Source>
            <summary>Gets a value that indicates the source that generated the notification, such as a change to the query data or the database's state.</summary>
            <value>The source of the notification.</value>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </Source>
        <Type>
            <summary>Gets a value that indicates whether this notification is generated because of an actual change, or by the subscription.</summary>
            <value>A value indicating whether the notification was generated by a change or a subscription.</value>
            <remarks>To be added.</remarks>
        </Type>
    </members>
</docs>
